Sanchit Goyal

CONTACT

#294-c, Phase-1 Model Town, Bathinda Punjab Website: www.linkedin.com/in/yolosanchit/

Phone: +91 78892-00068

ABOUT ME

Enthusiastic Javascript Developer with 4+ years of front end web development experience in designing cross browser compatible, performance optimized and responsive User Interfaces.

Also have experience in server side coding using Node & Express I am a passionate individual who is looking to grow by building a diverse set of skills & exploring new horizons of technology.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- **Proficient in:** JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Polymer.js, JQuery, Ajax, JSON, Gulp, Restful Services(REST API), MDL, JSX, Bootstrap.
- Familiar with:- Salesforce framework(SFCC),Node.js, Express.js, React.js, SQL, AngularJS.
- Also worked with :- Java, Python, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib
- Accessibility tools:- Talkback, NVDA
- Code versioning tools:- GIT/GitHub, Bitbucket
- IDE:- Visual Studio Code(VS Code)
- Development Methodology:- Agile/Scrum methodology

WORK EXPERIENCE

Publicis Sapient

Sept 2020 — Present

Senior Front End Developer

- Designed mega features for Coach that were reusable across multiple domains and supported in a range of devices with cross browser functionality.
- Also developed/integrated major features like megamenu, compare products, live chat,
- Wrote quality code with proper documentation keeping reusability in mind.

Publicis Sapient

Oct 2019 — August 2020

Front End Developer

- Revamped Cartier application, making production ready keeping in mind the tight timelines ./
- Developed multiple scalable/reusable features for Marriott International and enhanced application performance by reducing TLS handshake time b/w ajax calls by warming up pods on scaling.

Infosys (Finacle Product)

July 2017 — Oct 2019

Senior Systems Engineer

- Partnered with Team Leads and Product Owners to design and develop robust Banking solutions and enhanced application for functionality and performance (debouncing, throttling,etc).
- Designed User Interface for Banking application (+accessibility) and created many reusable components and performed Unit & System Testing manually for the modules built
- Implemented SMS banking in server side using Node.js & Express.js.

Sanchit Goval

Internship

 Designed an application that predicted a winner of a cricket match based on various factors. Performed Data Sanity and used Machine Learning(Regression Model) to train the models for the use case. Gained knowledge of Regression models & various Python libraries (Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Scikit Learn).

EDUCATION

B.Tech In Computer Engineering

Aug 2013 — June 2017

University College of Engineering, Punjabi University, Patiala

STRENGTHS

- Go-getter
- Adaptability
- Enthusiastic self learner
- Leadership
- Team Worker

Sanchit Goyal